my name is...module and today I'm going to present to talk connecting your devices to the as
your...sweet first of all a variety
sweet makes it easy to securely can make millions of devices to your
the application...and the
...dis can be done to receive telemetry and, the same commands not only that
...id swede is designed for multiply from devices n multiply from back
ends before we start going the deeper in the agenda let's start and,
see what to talk is going to...about what we're going to start
by introducing device connectivity in the as...then
we're going to talk about device identity and provisioning and then we're going to go on to device
to cloud and cloud to device messages then we're going to talk about
...and monitoring this connectivity which is very important?
So, let let's assume that you have lots of devices and they can be of
...kinds they can be ip capable so able to connect to the internet directly
...they can be low-power imbedded devices that can only connect to personal
...networks things like ...or core protocols.
The ip capable devices can connect directly to measure coyote...to
these component...called ip hub that we're going...explore much more deeply in
this talk...throughcloud protocol gateway in kick in case that
this did these devices due to not into interface with a protocol that is
in natively supported by...the...the are the other devices the
...cannot connect to in ip network might need to have oder
...devices to mediate for them those devices article feel gateways and
...basically used to...communications between low-power and,
non ip capable devices with the...
On the on the back-end side the ip hub
allows a your event processing and inside components to receive telemetry
...and,...messages from your from your devices components such as address
...stream analytics a or advise you storm can allow you to process
these data at very high scale your application runtime logic data that send might
...to send commands and receive requests from devices and that can also use the
...the hub to mediate...commands and...
request reply patents finally you you're going to have in your back and
...device provisioning and,
management component that will make sure that...did all your devices that and
...you have in the field are kind ofare correctly configured and work as expected?
And, in this talk...we're going to specifically focus on
how the devices can connect to ip hub and how all the parts of your
back-end can it can interacted out the hub to communicate with...devices?
There of course many aspects to connectivity the
first one is functionality the this can be very simple messages like device to
cloud or cloud to devices and the but you can also inc include
order form of communications like bulk uploads and downloads of files
there are also many kind of a securities that are...
security concerns that are important...in addressing device
connectivity and they can be the security of the device of the cloud of the channel
in this specific talk we're just going to talk about granting access rights
to devices to the imc the sweet and...not for the
...security and end-to-end there is an order talk in build that
the talks about ...security in end-to-end aspect please look,
at that toc.
Another aspect is very important is monitoring in...many io
...solutions devices cannot be reach
to be besides using network communications in
...cases any form of...function of the communication
if a effectively prevents the troubleshooting and, management of the
devices...this is why the other id sweet and...
component allows you to have to monitor the connectivity of the device and,
receive
feedbacks and events on what is happening in all those channels for all of your devices.
Finally and also not less important than anything else
our reach and customization casualty
...has as a goal to be able to connect to all possible to
being like very small low-power and embedded devices running
...to linux devices windows devices so on also
we want to enabled...the use of any protocol
data you might be using we are aware that...solutions are most often
from filled and...already lasso investment in.
Existing network protocols finally we also want to support
custom authentication schemes so not only...that are...first as...the first
...enable out of any other authentication scheme said you did you already
have...implemented or are required to use in your solution?
Let's go on and the
talk a little bit deeper about ip hub first...have is
designed for ip is a service the data is a component
of a variety suite that allows you to connect millions of devices to a petition
back-end this is to provide cloud skill communications device to clouding
...to devices in the form of doable messages probe providing a least one
semantics this allows you and, you and your application to focus on the actual
booting business logic and not on complicated retry and,
the and reliability patterns.
A...help...high-density gateway that allows some millions of
...simultaneously connected devices this
th this is very important when you actually have loss of devices and
...you need them to be reachable at any point in time.
...hub supports
...cloud spacing feedback regarding delivery of
receipts and expiration of messages and also for
any device communication errors this is fundamental in ninety solutions.
Ip hubble's who...supports per device authentication allowing
...each device as specific
...a identity and a set of security credentials
the then not only that but each device actually can
multiplex all the connections to a coyote...on the same connection
the this is critical to save resources both...the device side and on the cloud
side any for...is of course...protocol and moving platform.
Let's talk about dn pointed...how exposes on the once on
the device side each device has a couple of endpoints one to
...to receive messages of course the gateways which
...represent multiple the devices and can and, can operate over
multiple of this endpoints again on a single multiplex connections?
On the on the back inside I...has a
...endpoint for device to cloud messages which is usually used by your
event processing component...your devo in your device runtime logic
your device runtime logic also in the interact with the cloud to device
and endpoint which allows you to the send messages to the devices and,
also to your feedback and monitoring and endpoint to make sure that
...messages correctly arrive and, implementretry
logic where that is required finally your back and also...have
a device provisioning and management component which will definitely in into
...i-hub to keep did device identity in sync and,...
up-to-date with your the master device registry.
And,...have also exposes...have management
and point which allows you to configure parameters for performance say
security and functionality of...the help component in your solution.
Of course the as your
...sweet ...will brew provide st case for of these endpoints
data will coming to different flavors there will be the device
facing st case that are aimed at the devices n feel gateways
...support many platforms and many languages on.
The other side will have investigated specific for in
...functionalities for your back...and...for clyde and for
...gateways that will again be a available in multiple languages.
During the stock we're going to talk about a simple scenario we will have simulated
...turbine that emits telemetry every second this simulated
...turbine we'll be simulating a
...as a state machine of a turbine that is a started
...stopped and of course we're going to be able to command this disturbing from the
The first step is to provision device due to will be a
portal that will update...the device registry with the identity of
...of a new turbine and will also updates...hub a
...effectively enabling connectivity for that simulated device,
device then we'll be able to connect
...hub and the emit telemetry every second on the on
the on the back-end and event processor will use the receive and points to process
those telemetry messages and to update the telemetry on the portal?
Finally...do portal will also be able to
send commands to start and stop the turbine...hub to
a each specific turbine the...the simulated device with execute
the command and...response through the device to cloud pipeline to
the...processor which will then update the command store keeping track of exactly what happened.
Let's see this demo...action.
I have here very simple portal where
there are already to device provision and you can also see the history of
comments those device hat...create a new device.
I can create a device with
any device id and what this will do it will provision
at device inside a device registry...in this case
...be collection and then create their identity in
sit inside ip hop not only that ip hub will intern generate a key
...that I will be using to connected to simulated...as
this device now I also have an event...or?
...already started here these are a messages that I was sending a
few minutes ago and then we can now start
...simulator turbine there will then start emitting ten
to telemetry about when speed related...torque and output our.
D in dd event processor should then be able to see
the truant to receive these messages like we see here
and in my portal the
...entry would be updated.
What happens now is that I can send a command to
To the new turbine to stop.
Actually this was the old turbine the to the
...to stop what I'm going to do here I'm going to click stop turbine.
I should have received.
To stop.
What's going to happen now is that in my due to stats.
Should basically...turbine is stopped and my?
And, my
...store should actually have...hit history right now for this stop
command now let's wait for the turbine to actually stop now we
see that it's stopped and what has happened is that device sent response for that
command that should appear that appeared here in my command store?
Of course we can also create.
The whole idea is to use these to have lots of these devices so we can of course start
...order turbine.
Which of course appear in here we'll
...look at the code snippets for this projects on how to create and,
the send this commands later in toc?
...let's talk now about device provisioning that is the first and,
very important step of creating and,...solution using a
id sweet device provisioning as is a term that...in this talk is
used to represent the making devices known to your...
...usually many subsystems that are involved we talked about a device registry
and ip hub but there could also be many orders...could be ...systems
that you have in your full solution not only that.
The concept of device identity that we're going to use in this
talk isrelated to the identity of a connectivity from a connectivity
perspective in your solution usually devices entity can be a much
more complex concept of...could be solutions that have complicit
...devices think about an airplane that has like
many different sub components all with different id and with different communication
sub devices also there are many concerns
some the you might have to map data the different form
of identity's depending on legal a or procedural
...requirements?
To have to explain better this concept will have here and an example of
a sample provisioning flo just to make sure to explain how this
might be represented in a real system and, the device could be provisioning you
could be provision at a manufacturing state into the system the first-time that it
connects it could be it is bootstrap to
...specific regional datacenter this is very common when the manufacturing is it
is a global corporation and,
there are many different regional datacenters that...have to manage the
individual devices to point is that a manufacturing time the
devicemight not be a ready associated with specific region
...not only that as a result of a customer into
...inter interaction then devices actually activated
and allowed to connect to the system as a result of some events
...that could be related to security or...other reasons it could also be
at activated and finally deprivation all of these steps are and,
the...various functionality data done to enable at any point of your provisioning
flow are very much application dependent and,
touch many systems in the specific talk we're just going to focus
...the once...relevant for connectivity
and there are basically two main components one is the...hub that is used for access and,
communication the other one is the device registry that is used for
...and discovering your devices based
on application-specific parameters think about ...specific
plenty of ...turbine or region or model number so,
on so forth?
On top of all of those systems
...provisioning process is driven by provisioning orchestration
which can use and other...x extensible set of provisioning
apis which help for the coordination between ip hub and your device registry but in
...is very much custom process of your own application.
...let's move now...the device identity concept in ip
hop...to the important
part is the to understand is that ip half-dozen maintain and identity registry
...contains per device security materials which are of course used to grant access to
...individual devices it does allow
in individual device blocking so you can enable or feasible each
...individual devices one thing that is very important is that it is not
allowed generic queries so if you
the most likely you will have to have a...device registry
input implemented in the your solution that is the
...store of the existence of a specific device identity.
The identity registry if a
...effectively enables authenticated communications and the and,
is used of course to ensure the
...of the devices that receive the cloud to device messages and also
ip hub doeslabel all the incoming messages width
...in the authentication method that was used to...that message and,
of course that...the...was used to send...message in the this way you
have full control on the dn
the authentication aspects of your solution also we
...sweet...to support as much as possible custom authentication schemes
...have you will be able to store your divisive entity in as
your active directory and also we allowed to...use of
...master key to connect
widely hub in case you want to implementer around completely custom authentication scheme?
Let's look now in the demo solution how the identity
registry was used to implement the to...turbine provisioning.
Here in visual studio we had
a class in my solution we had a class called device manager and the
...this I would I have of course my device registry
that is implemented in the inducted...and I have here my credentials
productively and...also have my...hub ...string that
is used to connect to my ip...then when a new devices provision?
I invoked is a
...provision device the method which checks if it turbine
exists...inserts...device in the device registry for
is first and second...interested in ip
hop you see here how it is very easy to create a new device
in side and, the hub what happens is that this is already
...created in...state which means that is allowed to
connect what I can also do is that of course I can create one that is disabled in
...my provisioning flows...requires.
...multi-step activation process also I can I
can also create a new.
A...specific key.
A specific keyin the in this way.
And, the soul and I do not
lead ip hub create my keys in the in this version
...only supporting the symmetric key but we'll support many different methods for of
per devices...authentication so and.
So, in this way I will be able to create.
A new symmetric key for my.
For my a device.
With the primary key.
And, of course in order to do key rolling.
...he as well.
Notice that I created the device
into device registry first and then in the identity registry this
is important because you do not want to have devices...identity registry
...not keeping track of somewhere else drawer like many ways to make
...to of operations
...you can keep track of the stayed inside your
...your device registry you can use workflow framework such as the durable task frameworks
...framework...run some top of as your service...but,
the idea is that once...is in the ip
...registry in the ip have identity registry you have to keep...can only be
...by device id.
Of course same idea for the and provisioning notice again that I remove
it before before on the on the in the from the identity registry and then from the
...be in case that if something happens I I'm not my maintaining
and, activated the device inside the identity registry with the potential security holes
also notice that to retrieved the key from the from
the identity registry is just like a very simple call of get device with the device
id and that's what happen from the portal when I clicked when they click get?
Ok, ...let's talk now about the device to cloud messages.
Those are you sent from device send endpoint
n received from the from the backend receive and,...
the device endpoint is used supports in qb
and https protocol and the service side
endpoints supports amp.
Protocols of course will provide st case for both of those endpoints
...messages are
the are the ones that are there are used to send the telemetry in the example that we showed.
This receive endpoints is completely compatible with event hops so it does
support the partition receiver and the
...and client-side checkpoint all the integrations for with...takes and,
html...storm...so on continue to work and,
any receiver that you have working with event
...is going to work with without hub as well.
I...have also has some extra services...in addition to.
To event hub for device to cloud messages it does support
millions of simultaneously connected...devices all of them sending telemetry
it does support per device authentication
...in supports connection multiplexing on the device side for your
the...to device and device to cloud traffic and also across
multiple devices for a gateway scenarios in the sample what happens is
...the simulated the...devices simulates the telemetry values and
...telemetry messages every second and any
...processor that is implemented with event processor host is
...receives these messages and publishes
the state on the on the telemetry portal of course any other way
to receive messages from event how can be used such as your stream analytics or eighteen
site storm not only that...after the...could be
this start hq since the start of your of your to of your even processing
pipeline so the data could go in this in storage or in analytics pipeline or
anything you want to do with this with this data then the last step is of course
elementary...chose the last telemetry values for each turbine?
Let's look at...of how this was mph?
Implemented in the demo first this is the turbine simulator let's start here
with the with the...simulation method which gives like a high-level overview of what
...what is happening here first we create a device
klein class and this is a class that connects to
...hub using the hub name the turbine id and the turbine
key then there is a simulation loop this...there is a there's a central
...in that sense every second there's of course are receive loop
there is receiving for commands also I want to say while this code is
in csharp mostly for clarity for during representation I will show
later in the talk to snippets of on how to do these operations with our cst k.
So, to simulation loop basically
...of updates the state machine transition and, then actually
...per performs the simulation step that updates
on my state variables regarding wind speed and,
torque and output...so on so forth let's look at on...on the central imagery
thread this is a very simple loop that happens every second
a new telemetry message is created here I
...the message with the turban id with the time stampa...
speed related speed so on so forth and then I quit a new messages by
encoding this object in jason of course the message can include any
...array body so you can use any form of encoding that you
...won t that is there is important that fits best your solution.
The then you just invoke to send event on your device client.
On the
under receiving and I have an event processor host.
You see here I just have an event how
...string this was an already existing the event
even processor host and I was able to reuse the code as is in the in
...ip hub I create my event processor host giving my event hub and
...and storage account this is the same thing you could do with
...storm or with...of course and then in my process events.
Ie process my events and I get my messages of course when I
have when the message is recognize as a telemetry message a
ie update my the turbine portal...by sending a call to the portal?
Let's move on to
...to device messages cloud to device messages are sent from the cloud of course
...sand endpoint n received by the device.
The interface on the device side is...and https.
And, on the send side is...
The most important a very important characteristics
of these messages is that they do support at least one semantics
did these messages are durable in order to accommodate for
...connected devices and the device has to knowledge
to the receipt the...means that after the message has been
re-re received device has to explicitly abandoned message
...it wants to...the message again in the
future or completed in order for it to be the deleted from the
...this is very important because device could fail processing the term
...been the de message...whatever reason and
...message will still will still be there for the messes to consume
and the next time the...is able to connect or to process...
This...is also have a time to live and the and ip hub
...receipts for...the recede of the messages so the successful
completion or the expiration of them this allows you to code a very efficient
re-re try logic in your in your back-end it is very common to have a
life-cycle for commands so when you send cloud to device message to
the device user correlated device to cloud messages for responses
...your event processor like we saw earlier is able to
...to distinguish between a telemetry message
...the response of a specific command also you will receive
...this feedback regarding the successful completion or expiration of the
commanded that allows you to try the commands if they are
if that makes sense for your for your business logic finally it's usually
...to store the command state in the command registry that allows you to keep
track of exactly what happened to reach command and what is the state of each of those?
In the sample scenario what happens is that the portal
...sense to command to the to ...individual turbine through
...cloud to device and endpoint and is also
stores to command in the command store the device?
Can accepts to stop and since our commands any can also reject
...that is not aware of this is very important in the case you
do support multiple versions of your of your devices not all commands are going to be
suppose to supported by every device?
Dues commands are also long-running and when they are completed
a or rejected a responses sent through the device to cloud...
endpoint event processor then use the correlation id property to
filter the responses from the telemetry in case of the responses the
de command is...is in the command store is updated with
the correct output outcome also disease like a very
simple tracking of the commands usually what happens is that is that you want to have
...component of your of your
backend in the form of a worker role or like the your?
...bow device logic handling this message and that can happen
by the putting a message in the service bus topics or q in order to
...this work and high scale.
Let's look at how the cloud to devicemessages were sent in the demo solution here in
the device registry I have a method cosign command and here.
The same thing happenscome...compared to the to...the provisioning
high create a command object update my command store.
then I send...using the service client disservice client uses
...come...string to be created and then creates a nuke you can
...send the...method to send...command message to a device id notice
again that the message can be anything in this case is just is just
...jason the document but it could be any bade array so if you want
use authorization frameworks or three-two used to do that.
Let's look at how...true turbine simulator handles...event.
Determine simulator when it starts it starts are receive loop
these receive loop effectively uses the device client...receive a
...method to wait for commands this receiver
saying takes time span as input in this case five minutes
there is a time-out that gives you a chance to do other things when you do not want
to spin when you do not want to have a tread waiting for
those commands during the whole time continuously and also?
This allows for the for connecting connectivity style
...effectively your device is not connected all the time this is verycommon
on meter connection where you want your device to wake up every a certain amount of
time and then received messages and the central imagery and then disconnect.
The received body is the serialized and, of course here
ifsomething goes wrong with the...I have to handle that condition and I said
the current command with the command when this happens I complete the message
...effect...effectively says wellthis effectively tells the...hub that this message
was successfully ...now what happens is that
since this is a long-running process when the start or the stop
open operation finishes this...called respond to commandis
invoked by the simulator and in this case what I do I just use
...send event to ...command response which is effectively
and updated command object notice how the command response has a correlation
id that is equal to the command id this is required to make sure that these
responses correlated on the back-end with the with the correct command?
In the event processor now I'm going to I I'm using
this correlation id property to understand if this is
a command outcome or if it's a
telemetrymessage and if it's a command outcome in this case I call this
...handle command response like we said this can
...something in the store it could trigger a command
lifecycle flow it could send a message in a service...topic or q
...to...this work in our...the in case you're using
a stream analytics or storm the do pattern would be exactly the same?
I said before that we would go on a show this snippets...how to do send and,
receives from see in this case we see here how ...as a
snippet of rc sdk on how to receive call backs here like is very
easy you create and...hub client and then you can set on notification
call back which is affect your receive inside your receive notification call back
you are effectively able to receive messages and to and,
to and, to operate on them it is inside this method you will
be required to complete or abandon those the messages.
After you have...ip...client you can of course.
Send...sense has sent telemetry message in here you see that there is a receive
confirmation call back which calls you back when you're actually finished sending all
...all the telemetry events this is important again in case for of
intermittent connections were in case of intermittently connected devices where you want
to close the connection and when you're done sending the telemetry this makes
...make sure that everything that you actually sent has actually been acknowledged by the
back-end...before you sever the connection?
Let's now talk about...feel gateways.
To use cases for clouding feel gateways are mostly protocol translation
or custom authentication this is of course be besides some specific up application
...you want to perform on-the-field in your
feel gateway we see for instance here that
...gate we could offer like protocol translations from abetween...and,
qb on the talking to i-hub also like any other custom protocol than
you did you might have in your own id solution feel gateways on the
other hand also allows you to interface with the with devices...are not ip
...could be devices that did have ...have protocol that...that are one on the
...ip network such as a zinc be or protocols there are not suited or
...or design for the public internet such as call-up
duality have capabilities for a gateways allows you to build
cloud gateways n feel gateways in a very easy way first
we allow connection multiplexing for multiple devices effectively means that
many devices connecting to a cloud gateway can still flow through a same connection from the
...gate...still maintaining their identity also
...sweet will provide you with an extensible already developed entity
...gateway that you're able to deploy and use in your own solutions there are a couple
of patterns that I want to talk about regarding gateways the first one is transparent
...opaque gateways...transparent gateway is a
gateway where device identity's are flowing through the gateway so the ip
have is aware that there are like multiple devices
connect intruded gateway and, each one of those can effectively have
their own specific identity in this case ip
hub can individually authenticate those devices and,...
of course...labeling coming messages and, the and handled the access control
...those specific devices by also being able to enable and,
...them in individually and opaque gateway on the other hand is a
gateway where it's a gateway that effectively is masking it's the
...downstream devices to ip hub so ip have is only aware of
the a...gateway identity and the identity of the
...devices that are...connective trudy gateway are managed at
the application-level this case is of course also support but the but the ip have
then cannot provide services for those downstream devices they cannot be
into individually enabled order disabled and,
of course incoming messages cannot be labeled and another big the distinctions
...is between...gateways and push gateways a push gateway is a
...has to translate between...the protocols...the protocol
...ip hub a exposes which device always connects to
...even to receive messages and the...instead through the
...the pattern of...devices that are acting as a little servers for many
...personal...network devices a
very common pattern is to have them actors...little servers so that
...receive calls when they want to be contact in this case the
...gateway has effectively to mediate between these two patterns which effectively means
...that it has to know in advance which devices
he's it's listening for and it is responsible for with respect to the idea help?
Monitoring the device connectivity is the final the
topic of...this presentation and it is
a very important in a for id solutions
I do solutionsmost often cannot reach the
devices besides network connectivity in this case anything that data
is affecting the device connectivity is a blocking error?
For this reason id hub does
expose and specific endpoint to relay to the
back-end all the things that it...of written...
regarding connectivity not only success successful cases but also
error conditions so events are going to be generated regarding the
device...connections and...wonder failing so for a connection you will know
...if devices trying to connect but we run credentials or with the
wrong protocol version or for disconnection events you will know if it has been a
clean disconnection or if for the connection was interrupted and timed out same things
for device errorsa device might have like errors trying-to central imagery or to receive
...depending on maybe for wrong versions
of firmware or component software this-is again, and, event hub compatible
endpoint this endpoint allows you to create very complex logic re-re
regarding device connectivity without having to maintain a
...high scale gateway data ip hub is doing for you.
So, for instance an example is
...complex device blocking logic let's assume
that you want todo you want to disable...if it tries to
...to authenticate many times with the wrong credentials?
In this case you.
Could have an address stream analytics job
...evaluating the number of failed connection
attempts per device and if something and,
if that than the number is greater than something like ten in the last two
hours you can raise and alarm these alarm could go inside I ot have and disabled
the device or let somebody know that the dead device might have a wrong key may be a
key rolling...was not executed properly for third there's a
malicious attack happening this kind of complex logic can happen
on any device error in any connection
and disconnection events because we're?
Going to let those information's available to you.
Finally I want to do direct
...watch...io t related sessions in build one is
...the microsoft vision for...there is a session regarding best practices for creating
oddity solutions with asher and finally the session that I
ready reference before is about the security concept for as your I
...services that talks about security end-to-end and not just
related to connectivity thank you very much for watching and enjoy the rest of build.